this problem asks us
to invoke a destructive method on
greeting
which is a local variable referencing
the string hello when we
output greeting on line 2 by passing it
as an argument to put us
we want the string goodbye to be printed
instead of hello
let's hop into irb and take a look at
the string method
g sub
again i'll create a local variable
greeting
and assign it to the string hello
when we invoke g sub we can pass in two
arguments
the first being the pattern that we want
to replace
in the calling string and the second
being what we want to replace it with
so in this example let's say that we
want to replace the
e in hello with a
and you can see that substitution this
is the non-destructive g sub method
however our problem description
specifically tells us to use a
destructive
method this non-destructive g-sub
will return a new string
however you can see that greeting still
points to our original string
a destructive method will modify that
string in place
and ruby provides a destructive g-sub
this g sub has a bang operator at the
end
so let's run the same example this time
with the destructive g
sub
and the return value appears to be the
same
however if we inspect the variable
greeting again you can see that the
string referenced by greeting was
actually modified in place
so this destructive g sub will work
perfectly for the problem we've been
given
[Music]
now in this case we want to replace the
string hello with the string goodbye
so we can actually pass in hello
as the pattern that we want to be
replaced
and we'll pass in the string goodbye as
our second argument
now let's run our code and see if it
outputs goodbye and it does
ruby provides a lot of handy string
methods for us
to learn more about g sub or any other
string method
take a look at the ruby documentation